Speaker 1 (higher-pitched voice): Mr Chairman, I oppose this bill. It is remarkable to me that as gas and grocery prices go up because of this continued illegal war in Iran, as Americans pay tens of thousands
Woman 2: of dollars for health care because Republicans destroyed any semblance of health care with their Big Bad Betrayal Bill and cuts to the ACA subsidies,
As
Woman 2: Donald Trump enriched himself last year to the tune of 2.2 billion dollars while fleecing Americans of their hard-earned money, what are we spending time on? Once again, on targeting young trans people who make up less than one-half of one percent of the population. I would ask the majority,
Why
Woman 2: are you spending so much time manufacturing a culture war targeting a group of young people who make up less than one-half of one percent of the population? Is it perhaps because you want to fear-monger about them so that you distract people from the daily troubles that they have of keeping a roof over their head and paying for their health care and groceries?
Woman 2: Is it because you literally have no productive proposals to make life better for the American people? Is it because you want to distract attention away, once again, from the fact that ICE just killed two people in Texas and in Maine because Republicans refuse to hold them accountable and are spending $170 billion on these agencies instead of Americans' health care?
Woman 2: Or maybe you're trying to distract from Donald Trump refusing to sign into law the most significant bipartisan bill in a generation to invest in housing. Yes, you heard me right. It was passed into law by big bipartisan majorities in both the House and the Senate, but Donald Trump refused to sign the bill because he says affordability is a, quote, "hoax." Tell that to the American people who are struggling to afford rent or buy a home.
Let
Woman 2: me be very clear. Trans people have always and will always exist. Republicans will try to negate the urgency of gender-affirming care by cherry-picking extreme examples of people who regret care. A review of gender-affirming care for transgender youth conducted by the Utah legislature found that, quote, there is virtually no regret associated with receiving treatments.
And
Woman 2: that is why nearly every major medical association recognizes the importance of gender-affirming care for young trans people and have standards in place to ensure that this care can be provided responsibly.
What is
Woman 2: true is that for most trans youth, care simply comes in the form of puberty-pausing medications after close consultation with youth, their parents, and their medical providers. These medications have been prescribed safely for both
non
Woman 2: transgender and transgender children for decades. Trans patients use them at exactly the same doses and for exactly the same outcomes as their non-transgender counterparts. Now just an hour ago, the Secretary of Forever Wars, Pete Hagseth,
Woman 2: said that they are going to provide hormone therapy for male service members who don't have enough testosterone. This, by the way, is gender-affirming care. And by the way, male members of this committee, watch what you vote for.
Do
Woman 2: you really want the government getting into your business, taking your testosterone levels and determining whether or not you have enough testosterone? Are you male enough to be in Congress? That is the question. Now to go from the absurd to the very, very, very serious, in the past year,
Woman 2: 40% of transgender and non-binary young people seriously considered attempting suicide. Instead of shaming and targeting them for seeking the care they need, as Republicans constantly do, let us provide support to them.
Woman 2: This bill is so extreme that even mental health professionals could
Speaker 1 (higher-pitched voice): face legal action for talking to trans youth about the options they have available to live an authentic life. To
Americans who
Speaker 1 (higher-pitched voice): are frustrated, you are right to be frustrated. To trans people who are listening, you have every right to be fully who you are. Your freedom is not a threat to anyone else's and we will stand up and never throw you under the bus. I yield back.